LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brenda-thompson
Portfolio: https://github.com/BrendaTH

Summary

Experienced software engineer with a bachelor's degree in computer science and mathematics. Recently (September 2019) earned a certificate from the University of New Hampshire in Full Stack Development. Maintains an enthusiasm for many different technologies and languages, a generalist approach in career development, learns quickly, goal oriented.

Technical Skills

Experience in networking, embedded systems, C, micro-code, Bidirectional Forwarding Detection (BFD), fast path, hash tables, High Availability, working with geographically diverse groups, PHP, JavaScript, React, Agile, Linux

Relevant Experience

Ericsson, Acton, MA

Feb 2014 – Dec 2018

Member of Janus Client Team – Software developer/Agile scrum lead on HTML5 video client on browser. Written in JavaScript with Selenium unit tests.

Azuki Systems, Acton, MA (purchased by Ericsson in Feb 2014)

Sept 2012 – Feb 2014

Member of Professional Services Team:

Delivered Cablelabs OLCA based (Online Content Access Specification) Service Provider (in PHP) - part of Azuki's overall authentication strategy.

CISCO Systems Inc, Boxborough, MA

2000 - Sept 2011

Member of METRO-E Team:

June 2010 – Present

L2 RIB (Routing Information Database) for OTV (Overlay Transport Virtualization) project on ASR1k Router. Responsibilities included high availability (HA) support, event manager, and database redistribution, client database registration, and debug/logs/statistics. All code was written in C for CISCO IOS and required white box unit tests to be written at the same time.

Member of Advanced Network Transport Team:

Feb 2006 – June 2010

Platform independent Bidirectional Forwarding Detection (BFD) – written in C for IOS. Included BFD HA for the 6500/7600 Routers. Also supplied guidance and point of contact support for MPLS technical matters for a five member contractor team out of Chennai, India.

Member of ACE Health Probe Team:

June 2005 – March 2006

Ongoing support of Health Probes on Cisco's Application Control Engine module (ACE), a server load balancing module for the Catalyst 6500. All code written in C.

Member of GSS (Global Site Selector) team:

March 2004 – June 2005

Cisco's Global Server Load Balancer. Provided support for Health Probes/KALs (keep alive) to ensure the ongoing validity of the DNS answers/routes. All code was written in C++.

Arrowpoint Communications, Acton MA (purchased by Cisco July 2000)

2000 -- 2004

Member of CSS Fastpath Team:

January 2000 – March 2004

Wrote fastpath microcode for Arrowpoint/CISCO Content Services Switch (CSS) 11500, a stand-alone server load balancer. The fastpath was implemented on a Vitesse IQ2000 and written in MIPS assembly. Among other things the fastpath included L2 VLAN/802.1Q support, stateful TCP flow tracking, and network address and port translation (NAT).

Education

Bootcamp Certificate: University of New Hampshire Sept 2019 A 24 week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, React.

BS; Computer Science and Mathematics; UAH - University of Alabama, Huntsville, AL;